myseniorportal.com 2011-03-11

# Privacy policy

Our privacy policy is designed to help you understand how we collect and use any personal information you decide to share. and help make informed decisions when using My Senior Portal, located at myseniorportal.com

By using or accessing My Senior Portal you are accepting the practices described in this Privacy Policy.

We developed My Senior Portal to make it easy to find information, benefit from the resources available on the internet, share information with others and develop a way to store and share valuable personal and familial information. We understand you may not want everyone in the world to have the information you share on My Senior Portal which is why we give you control of your information. Our default privacy settings limit the information displayed in your profile and store most personal information only on your personal computer system.

My Senior Portal follows two core principles:

  1. You should have control over your personal information.
My Senior Portal helps you share information with your friends and people around you. You choose what information you put in your profile, including contact and personal information, pictures, interests and groups you join. And you control the users with whom you share that information through the privacy settings on the Privacy page. 
  2. You should have access to the information others want to share. There is an increasing amount of information available out there, and you may want to know what relates to you, your friends, and people around you. We want to help you easily get that information. Sharing information should be easy. And we want to provide you with the privacy tools necessary to control how and with whom you share that information. If you have questions or ideas, please check out our privacy help page.

Safe Use of My Senior Portal

For information for users and parents about staying safe on My Senior Portal, click here.

My Senior Portal’s Privacy Policy

My Senior Portal's Privacy Policy is designed to help you understand how we collect and use the personal information you decide to share, and help you make informed decisions when using My Senior Portal, located at www.My Senior Portal.com and its directly associated domains (collectively, "My Senior Portal" or "Website")

By using or accessing My Senior Portal, you are accepting the practices described in this Privacy Policy.

My Senior Portal is a licensee of the TRUSTe Privacy Program. TRUSTe is an independent, non-profit organization whose mission is to build user's trust and confidence in the Internet by promoting the use of fair information practices. This privacy statement covers the site www.My Senior Portal.com and its directly associated domains. Because this Web site wants to demonstrate its commitment to your privacy, it has agreed to disclose its information practices and have its privacy practices reviewed for compliance by TRUSTe.

If you have questions regarding this statement, please visit our privacy help page. If you do not receive acknowledgement of your inquiry or your inquiry has not been satisfactorily addressed, you should contact TRUSTe Watchdog at http://www.truste.org/consumers/watchdog_complaint.php. TRUSTe will then serve as a liaison with us to resolve your concerns.

EU Safe Harbor Participation

We participate in the EU Safe Harbor Privacy Framework as set forth by the United States Department of Commerce. As part of our participation in the safe harbor, we have agreed to TRUSTe dispute resolution for disputes relating to our compliance with the Safe Harbor Privacy Framework. If you have any complaints regarding our compliance with the Safe Harbor you should visit our Help Center. If contacting us does not resolve your complaint, you may raise your complaint with TRUSTe at http://www.truste.org/users/users_watchdog_intro.html.

The Information We Collect

When you visit My Senior Portal you provide us with two types of information: personal information you knowingly choose to disclose that is collected by us and Web Site use information collected by us as you interact with our Web Site. When you register with My Senior Portal, you provide us with certain personal information, such as your name, your email address, your telephone number, your address, your gender, schools attended and any other personal or preference information that you provide to us.

When you enter My Senior Portal, we collect your browser type and IP address. This information is gathered for all My Senior Portal visitors. In addition, we store certain information from your browser using "cookies." A cookie is a piece of data stored on the user's computer tied to information about the user. We use session ID cookies to confirm that users are logged in. These cookies terminate once the user closes the browser. By default, we use a persistent cookie that stores your login ID (but not your password) to make it easier for you to login when you come back to My Senior Portal. You can remove or block this cookie using the settings in your browser if you want to disable this convenience feature.

When you use My Senior Portal, you may set up your personal profile, form relationships, send messages, perform searches and queries, form groups, set up events, add applications, and transmit information through various channels. We collect this information so that we can provide you the service and offer personalized features. In most cases, we retain it so that, for instance, you can return to view prior messages you have sent or easily see your friend list. When you update information, we usually keep a backup copy of the prior version for a reasonable period of time to enable reversion to the prior version of that information.

You post User Content (as defined in the My Senior Portal Terms of Use) on the Site at your own risk. Although we allow you to set privacy options that limit access to your pages, please be aware that no security measures are perfect or impenetrable. We cannot control the actions of other Users with whom you may choose to share your pages and information. Therefore, we cannot and do not guarantee that User Content you post on the Site will not be viewed by unauthorized persons. We are not responsible for circumvention of any privacy settings or security measures contained on the Site. You understand and acknowledge that, even after removal, copies of User Content may remain viewable in cached and archived pages or if other Users have copied or stored your User Content.

Any improper collection or misuse of information provided on My Senior Portal is a violation of the My Senior Portal Terms of Service and should be reported through the Help Center.

If you choose to use our invitation service to tell a friend about our site, we will ask you for information needed to send the invitation, such as your friend's email address. We will send your friend an email or instant message in your name inviting him or her to visit the site, and may send up to two reminders to them. My Senior Portal stores this information to send invitations and reminders, to register a friend connection if your invitation is accepted, to allow you to see invitations you have sent, and to track the success of our referral program. Your friend may contact us through the Help Center to request that we remove this information from our database.

My Senior Portal may also collect information about you from other sources, such as newspapers, blogs, instant messaging services, and other users of the My Senior Portal service through the operation of the service (e.g., photo tags) in order to provide you with more useful information and a more personalized experience.

By using My Senior Portal, you are consenting to have your personal data transferred to and processed in the United States.

Children Under Age 13

My Senior Portal does not knowingly collect or solicit personal information from anyone under the age of 13 or knowingly allow such persons to register. If you are under 13, please do not attempt to register for My Senior Portal or send any information about yourself to us, including your name, address, telephone number, or email address. No one under age 13 may provide any personal information to or on My Senior Portal. In the event that we learn that we have collected personal information from a child under age 13 without verification of parental consent, we will delete that information as quickly as possible. If you believe that we might have any information from or about a child under 13, please contact us through the form on our privacy help page.

Children Between the Ages of 13 and 18

We recommend that minors 13 years of age or older ask their parents for permission before sending any information about themselves to anyone over the Internet.

Use of Information Obtained by My Senior Portal

When you register with My Senior Portal, you create your own profile and privacy settings. Your profile information, as well as your name and email, are displayed to people in the networks specified in your privacy settings to enable you to connect with people on My Senior Portal. We may occasionally use your name and email address to send you notifications regarding new services offered by My Senior Portal that we think you may find valuable.

Profile information is used by My Senior Portal primarily to be presented back to and edited by you when you access the service and to be presented to others permitted to view that information by your privacy settings. In some cases where your privacy settings permit it (e.g., posting to your wall), other My Senior Portal users may be able to supplement your profile.

Profile information you submit to My Senior Portal will be available to users of My Senior Portal who belong to at least one of the networks you allow to access the information through your privacy settings (e.g., school, geography, friends of friends). Your name, network names, and profile picture thumbnail will be available in search results across the My Senior Portal network and those limited pieces of information may be made available to third party search engines. This is primarily so your friends can find you and send a friend request. People who see your name in searches, however, will not be able to access your profile information unless they have a relationship to you (friend, friend of friend, member of your networks, etc.) that allows such access based on your privacy settings.

My Senior Portal may send you service-related announcements from time to time through the general operation of the service. For instance, if a friend sends you a new message or poke, or someone posts on your wall, you may receive an email alerting you to that fact.

Generally, you may opt out of such emails from the Notifications page, though My Senior Portal reserves the right to send you notices about your account even if you opt out of all voluntary email notifications.

My Senior Portal may use information in your profile without identifying you as an individual to third parties. We do this for purposes such as aggregating how many people in a network like a band or movie and personalizing advertisements and promotions so that we can provide you My Senior Portal. We believe this benefits you. You can know more about the world around you and, where there are advertisements, they're more likely to be interesting to you. For example, if you put a favorite movie in your profile, we might serve you an advertisement highlighting a screening of a similar one in your town. But we don't tell the movie company who you are.

We may use information about you that we collect from other sources, including but not limited to newspapers and Internet sources such as blogs, instant messaging services, My Senior Portal Platform developers and other users of My Senior Portal, to supplement your profile. Where such information is used, we generally allow you to specify in your privacy settings that you do not want this to be done or to take other actions that limit the connection of this information to your profile (e.g., removing photo tag links).

Sharing Your Information with Third Parties

My Senior Portal is about sharing information with others — friends and people in your networks — while providing you with privacy settings that restrict other users from accessing your information. We allow you to choose the information you provide to friends and networks through My Senior Portal. Our network architecture and your privacy settings allow you to make informed choices about who has access to your information. We do not provide contact information to third party marketers without your permission. We share your information with third parties only in limited circumstances where we believe such sharing is 1) reasonably necessary to offer the service, 2) legally required or, 3) permitted by you. For example:

  * Your News Feed may aggregate the information you provide and make it available to your friends and network members according to your privacy settings. You may set your preferences for your News Feed on your Privacy Settings page.
  * Unlike most sites on the Web, My Senior Portal limits access to site information by third party search engine "crawlers" (e.g. Google, Yahoo, MSN, Ask). My Senior Portal takes action to block access by these engines to personal information beyond your name, profile picture, and limited aggregated data about your profile (e.g. number of wall postings).
  * We may provide information to service providers to help us bring you the services we offer. Specifically, we may use third parties to facilitate our business, such as to host the service at a co-location facility for servers, to send out email updates about My Senior Portal, to remove repetitive information from our user lists, to process payments for products or services, to offer an online job application process, or to provide search results or links (including sponsored links). In connection with these offerings and business operations, our service providers may have access to your personal information for use for a limited time in connection with these business activities. Where we utilize third parties for the processing of any personal information, we implement reasonable contractual and technical protections limiting the use of that information to the My Senior Portal-specified purposes.
  * If you, your friends, or members of your network use any third-party applications developed using the My Senior Portal Platform ("Platform Applications"), those Platform Applications may access and share certain information about you with others in accordance with your privacy settings. You may opt-out of any sharing of certain or all information through Platform Applications on the Privacy Settings page. In addition, third party developers who have created and operate Platform Applications ("Platform Developers"), may also have access to your personal information (excluding your contact information) if you permit Platform Applications to access your data. Before allowing any Platform Developer to make any Platform Application available to you, My Senior Portal requires the Platform Developer to enter into an agreement which, among other things, requires them to respect your privacy settings and strictly limits their collection, use, and storage of your information. However, while we have undertaken contractual and technical steps to restrict possible misuse of such information by such Platform Developers, we of course cannot and do not guarantee that all Platform Developers will abide by such agreements. Please note that My Senior Portal does not screen or approve Platform Developers and cannot control how such Platform Developers use any personal information that they may obtain in connection with Platform Applications. In addition, Platform Developers may require you to sign up to their own terms of service, privacy policies or other policies, which may give them additional rights or impose additional obligations on you, so please make sure to review these terms and policies carefully before using any Platform Application. You can report any suspected misuse of information through the My Senior Portal Platform and we will investigate any such claim and take appropriate action against the Platform Developer up to and including terminating their participation in the My Senior Portal Platform and/or other formal legal action.
  * We occasionally provide demonstration accounts that allow non-users a glimpse into the My Senior Portal world. Such accounts have only limited capabilities (e.g., messaging is disabled) and passwords are changed regularly to limit possible misuse.
  * We may be required to disclose user information pursuant to lawful requests, such as subpoenas or court orders, or in compliance with applicable laws. We do not reveal information until we have a good faith belief that an information request by law enforcement or private litigants meets applicable legal standards. Additionally, we may share account or other information when we believe it is necessary to comply with law, to protect our interests or property, to prevent fraud or other illegal activity perpetrated through the My Senior Portal service or using the My Senior Portal name, or to prevent imminent bodily harm. This may include sharing information with other companies, lawyers, agents or government agencies.
  * We let you choose to share information with marketers or electronic commerce providers through on-site offers.
  * We may offer stores or provide services jointly with other companies on My Senior Portal. You can tell when another company is involved in any store or service provided on My Senior Portal, and we may share customer information with that company in connection with your use of that store or service.
  * My Senior Portal Beacon is a means of sharing actions you have taken on third party sites, such as when you make a purchase or post a review, with your friends on My Senior Portal. In order to provide you as a My Senior Portal user with clear disclosure of the activity information being collected on third party sites and potentially shared with your friends on My Senior Portal, we collect certain information from that site and present it to you after you have completed an action on that site. You have the choice to have My Senior Portal discard that information, or to share it with your friends.

To learn more about the operation of the service, we encourage you to read the tutorial here. To opt out of the service altogether, click here.

Like many other websites that interact with third party sites, we may receive some information even if you are logged out from My Senior Portal, or that pertains to non-My Senior Portal users, from those sites in conjunction with the technical operation of the system. In cases where My Senior Portal receives information on users that are not logged in, or on non-My Senior Portal users, we do not attempt to associate it with individual My Senior Portal accounts and will discard it.

If the ownership of all or substantially all of the My Senior Portal business, or individual business units owned by My Senior Portal, Inc., were to change, your user information may be transferred to the new owner so the service can continue operations. In any such transfer of information, your user information would remain subject to the promises made in any pre-existing Privacy Policy.

When you use My Senior Portal, certain information you post or share with third parties (e.g., a friend or someone in your network), such as personal information, comments, messages, photos, videos, Marketplace listings or other information, may be shared with other users in accordance with the privacy settings you select. All such sharing of information is done at your own risk. Please keep in mind that if you disclose personal information in your profile or when posting comments, messages, photos, videos, Marketplace listings or other items , this information may become publicly available.

Links

My Senior Portal may contain links to other websites. We are of course not responsible for the privacy practices of other web sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site to read the privacy statements of each and every web site that collects personally identifiable information. This Privacy Policy applies solely to information collected by My Senior Portal.

Third Party Advertising

Providers of goods and services that appear on My Senior Portal are sometimes delivered (or "served") directly to users by third party advertisers. They automatically receive your IP address when this happens. These third party advertisers may also download cookies to your computer, or use other technologies such as JavaScript and "web beacons" (also known as "1x1 gifs") to measure the effectiveness of their ads and to personalize advertising content. Doing this allows the advertising network to recognize your computer each time they send you an advertisement in order to measure the effectiveness of their ads and to personalize advertising content. In this way, they may compile information about where individuals using your computer or browser saw their advertisements and determine which advertisements are clicked. My Senior Portal does not have access to or control of the cookies that may be placed by the third party advertisers. Third party advertisers have no access to your contact information stored on My Senior Portal unless you choose to share it with them.

This privacy policy covers the use of cookies by My Senior Portal and does not cover the use of cookies or other tracking technologies by any of its advertisers.

Changing or Removing Information

Access and control over most personal information on My Senior Portal is readily available through the profile editing tools. My Senior Portal users may modify or delete any of their profile information at any time by logging into their account. Information will be updated immediately. Individuals who wish to deactivate their My Senior Portal account may do so on the My Account page. Removed information may persist in backup copies for a reasonable period of time but will not be generally available to members of My Senior Portal.

Where you make use of the communication features of the service to share information with other individuals on My Senior Portal, however, (e.g., sending a personal message to another My Senior Portal user) you generally cannot remove such communications.

Security

My Senior Portal takes appropriate precautions to protect our users' information. Your account information is located on a secured server behind a firewall. When you enter sensitive information (such as your password), we encrypt that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL). (To learn more about SSL, go to http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Secure_Sockets_Layer). Because email and instant messaging are not recognized as secure communications, we request that you not send private information to us by email or instant messaging services. If you have any questions about the security of My Senior Portal Web Site, please contact us through the Help Center.

Terms of Use, Notices and Revisions

Your use of My Senior Portal, and any disputes arising from it, is subject to this Privacy Policy as well as our Terms of Use and all of its dispute resolution provisions including arbitration, limitation on damages and choice of law. We reserve the right to change our Privacy Policy and our Terms of Use at any time. Non-material changes and clarifications will take effect immediately, and material changes will take effect within 30 days of their posting on this site. If we make changes, we will post them and will indicate at the top of this page the policy's new effective date. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here, by email, or through notice on our home page. We encourage you to refer to this policy on an ongoing basis so that you understand our current privacy policy. Unless stated otherwise, our current privacy policy applies to all information that we have about you and your account.
